Guide to the Barbara Guest Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, circa 1923-2004; Series V
  - Photographs of Guest and others
    - Greece, 1965 (Box 133, Folder 1914)
    - Photographs of places by Hadley, 1960s (Box 133, Folder 1915)
    - Solebury School, New Hope, PA, 1950s (Box 133, Folder 1916)
    - New York City, 1999 (Box 133, Folder 1917)
    - "Willi" sculpture by Tony Smith, undated (Box 133, Folder 1918)
    - Unidentified woman, undated (Box 134, Folder 1919-1920)
    - Family photographs, undated (Box 134, Folder 1921)
    - Photograph of Trumbull Higgins, 1930 (Box 134, Folder 1922)
    - Photograph of Trumbull Higgins, 1928 (Box 134, Folder 1923)
    - Barbara Guest, young, undated (Box 134, Folder 1924)
    - Unidentified boy, undated (Box 134, Folder 1925)
    - Unidentified man, undated (Box 134, Folder 1926)
    - Unidentified girl, undated (Box 134, Folder 1927)
    - Various family, undated (Box 134, Folder 1928)
    - Guest with composer Gian Carlo Menotti, 1965 (Box 135, Folder 1929)
    - Bryher at Kenwin in Switzerland; Guest and Bryher, 1977 October (Box 135, Folder 1930)
    - Photographs of Guest and friends, 1940–1997 (Box 135, Folder 1931)
    - Guest, 1998 October (Box 135, Folder 1932)
    - Guest on Olive Hill by Frank Lloyd Wright, taken by Edmund Teske, 1940 (Box 135, Folder 1933)
    - Photograph of sculpture "Tau" by Tony Smith, 1968 (Box 135, Folder 1934)
    - Sermoneta, Italy, 1965 (Box 135, Folder 1935)
    - Unidentified, 1990–2000 (Box 135, Folder 1936)
    - Naropa Institute and Berkeley, CA, 1998–1999 (Box 135, Folder 1937)
    - Chicago, Illinois, 1998 October (Box 135, Folder 1938)
    - New York City with friends, Barnard, 1999 April (Box 135, Folder 1939)
    - Seattle, Vancouver, and Berkeley, 1999 August (Box 135, Folder 1940)
    - Guest in New York City, 1999 December (Box 135, Folder 1941)
    - 1301 Milvia Street, Rena Rosenwasser, 2000 April (Box 135, Folder 1942)
    - Fay Lansner and Barbara Guest collaboration, undated (Box 135, Folder 1943)
    - Guest and Kiki Smith, San Francisco, 1999 (Box 135, Folder 1944)
    - Guest, 2000 September 6 (Box 135, Folder 1945)
    - Photographs of rented house, Berkeley, 1998 December (Box 135, Folder 1946)
    - Guest in New York City, 1965 (Box 136, Folder 1947)
    - Guest, circa 1940 (Box 136, Folder 1948)
    - "Poets and Artists", 1960s (Box 136, Folder 1949)
    - Photographs by Hadley Guest, 2000–2003 (Box 136, Folder 1950)
    - Photograph of Guest, undated (Box 136, Folder 1951)
    - Family photographs sent by Don Tabor, 2002 (Box 136, Folder 1952)
    - Barbara Guest, Mary Abbott, Rena Rosenwasser, 2003 June (Box 137, Folder 1953)
    - 1301 Milvia Street, Berkeley CA, Winter (Box 137, Folder 1954)
    - Barbara Guest, undated (Box 137, Folder 1955)
    - Bennington College, 1967 (Box 137, Folder 1956)
    - Hadley Haden-Guest, undated (Box 137, Folder 1957)
    - Places, undated (Box 137, Folder 1958)
    - Guest and young man, undated (Box 138, Folder 1959)
    - Photograph and clipping from Good Housekeeping magazine on babysitting with photograph of Hadley, 1953 (Box 138, Folder 1960)
    - Guest, undated (Box 138, Folder 1961)
    - Unidentified people, undated (Box 138, Folder 1962)
    - Unidentified people, undated (Box 138, Folder 1963-1964)
    - Unidentified people, undated (Box 138, Folder 1965)
    - Photographs of an interior, undated (Box 139, Folder 1966)
    - Unidentified photographs and negatives, undated (Box 139, Folder 1967-1982)
  - Portraits
    - Portraits of Guest
      - Black, Star in Southampton, NY, 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1984-1985)
      - Dater, Judy, 2004 (Box 140, Folder 1986)
      - Dennis, Donna, circa 1960 (Box 140, Folder 1991)
      - Manley, Charles, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 1988-1989)
      - Melanga, Gerard, undated (Box 140, Folder 1992)
      - Frost medal awards in New York City, 1999 April (Box 140, Folder 1987)
      - In Sermoneta, Italy, 1965 (Box 140, Folder 1990)
    - Portraits of others, undated (Box 140, Folder 1993)
  - Photograph albums
    - Disassembled photograph album, 1947–1964 (Box 141, Folder 1994-2009)
    - "Barbara Guest Festschrift" Bonn University, 1994 April 12 (Box 142, Folder 2010)
    - "Photograph album of plays", undated (Box 142, Folder 2011)
    - Family photographs and postcards, undated (Box 142, Folder 2012)
  - "Photographs A-Z"
    - A, undated (Box 143, Folder 2014)
    - B, undated (Box 143, Folder 2015)
    - C, undated (Box 143, Folder 2016)
    - D, undated (Box 143, Folder 2017)
    - E, undated (Box 143, Folder 2018)
    - F, undated (Box 143, Folder 2019)
    - G, undated (Box 143, Folder 2020)
    - H, undated (Box 143, Folder 2021)
    - K, undated (Box 143, Folder 2022)
    - M, undated (Box 143, Folder 2023)
    - N, undated (Box 143, Folder 2024)
    - P, undated (Box 143, Folder 2025)
    - R, undated (Box 143, Folder 2026)
    - T, undated (Box 143, Folder 2027)
    - XYZ/Special, undated (Box 143, Folder 2028)
- Artwork, 1953-1995; Series VI
  Arranged alphabetically by artist. A notebook is filed at the end.
  This series contains artwork by several artists. One work is a comic collaboration between Guest and Joe Brainard and the other works were created by or for Guest to use as published cover art.
  - Brainard, Joe and Barbara Guest. Comic (Box 155, Folder 2029)
  - Dunn, Ann. Original art for Stripped Tales, 1995 (Box 155, Folder 2030-2031)
  - Dunn, Ann. Paintings for "The Magic City Series", undated (Box 155, Folder 2032-2033)
  - Dunn, Ann. Artwork for "If So, Tell Me", undated (Box 155, Folder 2034)
  - Guest, Barbara. Collage for Rocks on a Platter bookjacket, 1953 (Box 155, Folder 2036)
  - Reid, Laurie. Art for Symbiosis, undated (Box 155, Folder 2035)
  - Sketchpad, undated (Box 155, Folder 2037)
- Printed Material, 1960-2004; Series VII
  Organized into two subseries: Publications related to Guest and Printed material collected by Guest
  This series contains printed material related to Guest and printed material assembled by Guest.
  - Publications related to Guest
    - Printed material, undated (Box 157, Folder 2045-2065)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 158, Folder 2066-2092)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 159, Folder 2093-2101)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 160, Folder 2102-2115)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 161, Folder 2116-2124)
  - Printed material collected by Guest
    - Various printed material, undated (Box 162, Folder 2125-2129)
    - Various printed material, undated (Box 163, Folder 2130-2135)
    - Various printed material, undated (Box 164, Folder 2136-2141)
    - Various printed material, undated (Box 165, Folder 2142-2152)
- Audiovisual Material, 1963-2000; Series VIII
  Organized into four subseries: Reel-to-reel audiotapes, Audiocassettes, Videocassettes, and Sound discs.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 144-152 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
  This series includes reel-to-reel audiotapes, audiocassettes, videocassettes, and phonograph records. The material contains readings, interviews, research material, and other related content.
  - Reel-to-reel audiotapes
    - 7" reels: copies made in October 1996
      - Tape 1: Interview with Bryher, 1.0 (Box 144)
        Original recorded date unknown
      - Tape 2: Barbara Guest on Jeap Aro, 2.0 (Box 144)
        Original recorded 1989 November 30
      - Tape 3: Barbara Guest- The Location of Things, 2.0 (Box 144)
      - Tape 4: Seeking Air- read by Barbara Einzig, Susan Howe, and Maureen Owen, 2.0 (Box 144)
      - Tape 5: James Schuyler- Hymn to Life and Other Poems, 1.0 (Box 144)
      - Tape 6: Poets Readings in the Village, 1.0 (Box 144)
      - Tape 7: Poets Reading in the Village: James Schuyler, 1.0 (Box 144)
      - Tape 8: Great Neck Library, Barbara Guest, 2.0 (Box 144)
        Original recorded 1983 October 16
      - Tape 9: Tape 9 copy Bryher 1976 Burier-La-Tour, 2.0 (Box 144)
      - Tape 10: copy- Laura (Riding) Jackson- tape for Manhattan Theatre Club, 2.0 (Box 145)
        Original recorded 1983 March 28
      - Tape 11: copy- Barbara Guest WBAI interview 60 m continued, 1.0 (Box 145)
      - Tape 12: Barbara Guest Interview Susan Howe, 2.0 (Box 145)
      - Tape 13: "The Creative Process" by Barbara Guest and Mary Abbott. University of illinois, 2.0 (Box 145)
        Original recorded 1975 November 17
      - Tape 14: "Poetry" Side 1 and 2 by Barbara Guest and Mary Abbott. University of illinois, 1.0 (Box 145)
      - Tape 15: On the Writings of Laura (Riding) Jackson, Manhattan Theatre Club; Jeanne Lance- Introduction, Theodore Wilenz- "The Life" Sonia Raiziss- Poetry, Barbara Guest, 2.0 (Box 145)
      - Tape 16: copy- Barbara Guest Reading at St. Mark's Poetry Project, 2.0 (Box 145)
        Original recorded 1978 December 13
      - [Tape 17] Unidenfitied tape, 1.0 (Box 145)
      - Tape 18: Pen Portraits- John Ashberry and Barbara Guest, 2.0 (Box 146)
        Original recorded 1977 February 1
      - Tape 19: Readings from The Location of Things and Poems, Barbara Guest, 2.0 (Box 146)
      - Tape 20: Barbara Guest Higgins reading from The Location of Things, 2.0 (Box 146)
      - Tape 21: Barbara Guest Interview- copy of Master WBAI for Susan Howe, 1.0 (Box 146)
    - 10" reel
      - Barbara Guest Interview copy of Master WBAI for Susan Howe, 1.0 (Box 147)
  - Audiocassettes
    - "poetry and painting" Barbara Guest and Mary Abbott, University of Minnesota in Minneapolis, 1976; 1 (Box 149)
    - Charles North reading at St. Mark's Poetry Project, 1978-12-13; 1 (Box 149)
    - Interview with Bryher at Burier-La-Tou, Switzerland, Barbara Guest is interviewer, 1979-01; 1 (Box 149)
    - Barbara Guest: WBAI interview, 1979; 1 (Box 148)
    - Bryher, Buren-la-Tour, 1979; 1 (Box 149)
    - Seeking Air read by Barbara Einzig, Susan Howe, and Maureen Owen, introduced by Kathleen Fraser, 1980-01-25; 1 (Box 149)
    - H.D. Reading from "Helen in Egypt", 1980; 1 (Box 149)
    - Watershed tape #171, Barbara Guest, 1982; 1 (Box 148)
    - On the Writings of Laura (Riding) Jackson, 1983-03-28; 1 (Box 149)
    - Laura (Riding) Jackson, tape for Manhattan Theatre Club, 1983-03-28; 1 (Box 149)
    - Great Neck Library, Barbara Guest, 1983-10-16; 1 (Box 149)
    - Trumbull Higgins: "Hitler in Russia", World Affairs Council at Southampton College, 1984-11-17; 1 (Box 148)
    - PEN Oakland, Josephine Miles Book Awards, Pro Arts Oakland, 1986-05-18; 1 (Box 149)
    - Poets' Corner Live: Barbara Guest, WPBX, 1986-12-14; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest on Jean Arp, Poets House, 1989-11-30; 1 (Box 149)
    - Poets Reading in the Village, tape 2, James Schuyler, 1991-02-06; 1 (Box 149)
    - Poets Reading in the Village, tape 1, Barbara Guest, 1991-02-06; 1 (Box 149)
    - Barbara Guest: The Voice Box, London, 1992-04-26; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest, 1994-01-11; 1 (Box 148)
    - Forum: Entertainment, KQED-FM, 1994-11-11; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest interviewed by Kathleen Fraser at Kelsey St. Press Salon, 1995-01-22; 1 (Box 148)
    - "Among [phone] messages (previous) by means unknown in undetected conversation between Barbara and Hadley", 1995-05-05; 1.0 (Box 148)
      "On tape used for telephone messages (toward end of tape)"
    - Barbara Guest interviewed by Jack Foley "Cover to Cover" KPFA-FM, 1996-03-13; 1 (Box 148)
    - Bookworm, produced by Michael Silverblatt and Melinda Seigel for KCRW, 1996-04-16; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest interview, 1996-11-02; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest at UCSC, 1997-05-15; 1 (Box 148)
    - Naropa W&P Reading with Guest, Gizzi, Berssenbrugge, 1998-06-25; 1 (Box 148)
    - Reading-Naropa, 1998; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest interview by poet Mei-Mei Berssenbrugge. Introduction by Ann Waldman at the Naropa Institute in Boulder, Colorado, 1998-06-18; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest KSUS Reading at Kootenay School of Writing, 1999-08-14; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest KSW Talk, 1999-08-15; 1 (Box 148)
    - LINEbreak: Interviews and performance from the Literary Edge with Charles Bernstein, undated; 1 (Box 148)
    - Bonne Anniversaire!!!: Norma Cole, Barbara Guest, Benjamin Hollander, Michael Palmer, Mary Margaret Sloan, Cole Swensen. A Small Press Traffic salute to Anne-Marie Albiach on her 60th birthday, undated; 1 (Box 148)
    - Barbara Guest: The Location of Her". Talk by Kathleen Fraser for Brown University, 1994-03-28; 1 (Box 148)
    - Poets reading from their work, from the Thomas Edison Archives, undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - The Making of Americans: Parts 1 and 2, Gertrude Stein Reads, undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - "the creative process", undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - Barbara Guest WBAI interview, undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - Barbara Guest: The Location of Things, Watershed Tapes, undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - Christine at the Higgins for Easy 2 Uncle Johnny, undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - Trumbull, undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - Barbara Guest-interview with Susan Howe, undated; 1 (Box 149)
    - James Schuyler: Hymn to Life and Other Poems, undated; 1 (Box 149)
  - Videocassettes
    - The American Poetry Archive, 1974-02-14; 1 (Box 150)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 1979-05-16; 1 (Box 150)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 1983-01-09; 1 (Box 150)
    - Women Working in Literature, written and narrated by Kathleen Fraser, 1991; 1 (Box 151)
    - The Poetry Center and American Poetry Archives at San Francisco State University: Barbara Guest, 1993-05-20; 1 (Box 150)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 1993-05-20; 1 (Box 150)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 1995-03-23; 1 (Box 150)
    - Other Lives: Barbara Guest and Susan Gevitz, 1995-11-15; 1 (Box 150)
    - Barbara Guest, two readings, SF Poetmuseum, Cloud House Poetry Archives, 1995-1996; 1 (Box 150)
    - Lannan Literary Videos: Barbara Guest, 1996-04-16; 1 (Box 150)
    - Barbara Guest: Lannan Literary Videos, 1996; 1 (Box 150)
    - 3 Plays by Barbara Guest: Port/The Office/Often, 2000-12-08; 1 (Box 151)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 2001-03-04; 1 (Box 151)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 2001-03-04; 1 (Box 150)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 2001-03-04; 1 (Box 150)
    - The American Poetry Archive, 2001-03-04; 1 (Box 151)
    - Barbara Guest Reading at Mills College, 2002-12; 1 (Box 150)
    - Barbara Guest, USF/Lone Mountain, SF Poetmuseum documentary, 2003-10-10; 1 (Box 151)
  - Phonograph records
    - "T.S. Eliot reads 'The Hollow Men'", 1.0 (Box 152)
    - "T.S. Eliot reads 'Gerontion'", 1.0 (Box 152)
    - "Casper Citron WRFM", 1963 March 25; 1.0 (Box 152)